Morning,
领导
boss.
早啊
[Finished your report already]
是不这报告写完了
[and have nothing to do?]
没工作可做了
I do have work.
有啊
Watching funny videos in the morning
早起看搞笑视频
helps me
能让一天的工作
stay energized all day.
更有精神
Seems like
我看你工作
you're not busy enough.
还是不够饱和呀
I heard you
还有工夫
play matchmaker
去给同事
for your colleagues.
介绍相亲对象
How about this,
这样吧
you help with the high-tech certification
二期园区那个
for the
电子软件的
electronics software company
企业专精特新申报
in Phase Two of the Tech Park.
你配合着一块处理
This is thankless task...
这费力不讨好的事
I'll do it.
干
Came in too early.
还是来得太早
Morning, Jing.
姐 早
Morning.
早
Awfully chipper today.
过于精神了吧
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
you're looking
今儿
exceptionally radiant today.
过于光鲜亮丽了吧
What do you mean?
不是我哪天
I always look radiant, don't I?
不光鲜亮丽啊
Don't you
你
remember?
都不记得了
Remember
我
what?
应该记得什么
Last night,
昨天晚上
you
你
and me,
和我
about that...
那个
About what?
哪个
Speak clearly.
你说话说清楚点
You're making it
好像
sound like
搞得我们俩
we have an improper relationship.
有不正当关系一样
What improper relationship?
什么不正当关系
Did you forget about
欠我钱的事情
the money you owe me?
你都忘了
I owe you money?
我欠你钱
You must be dreaming.
做梦呢吧你
Who's dreaming?
谁做梦了
You're so tight with money.
你铁公鸡一毛不拔
We will never have
咱俩能有经济上的来往
any financial dealings.
你能借我钱
Are you crazy?
疯了你
What are you talking about?
什么叫我这种人
Come with me.
你跟我过来
Where are you taking me?
我跟你上哪儿去
Don't get physical.
我告诉你别动手啊
Just look,
看就看啊
keep a safe distance.
保持安全距离
[Ma'am,]
女士您好
[I work in this bar.]
我是这家酒吧的服务员
[This gentleman]
据这位先生说
[is worried]
担心您
[you might deny the charges tomorrow...]
明天起来赖账
Wait,
你等会儿
skip that part.
这句 不用说
Let me start over.
那我重新来
No, just continue.
不用 你接着说
So,
所以呢
I'm recording a video
我配合他拍个视频
for proof.
给他呀做个证
You spent
今天呢您在我们这儿
8000 yuan here today,
消费了八千元
and this gentleman paid the bill.
全是这位先生垫的
It has nothing to do with him.
跟他一点关系都没有
Keep talking.
没事你说你的
Who's denying charges?
谁赖账
Nothing to do with him.
就是 跟他毫无关系
Then, we need...
然后 需要
What proof?
做什么证啊
Just give me another...
你就再给我
Ignore her, continue.
不用管她你说
Careful, ma'am.
小心 女士
Ma'am!
女士 女士
That one's more expensive!
那个更贵
Don't touch that!
那个你可别碰啊
-Open the bottle for me! -Come here!
开吗 过来 过来
Pull out that chair
你把那个椅子给拉出来
and let her sit.
让她坐着
Delete the video.
删了
No way.
不可能删
If I delete it,
我删了
what if you don't pay me back?
你不还我钱怎么办
Besides,
再说
this is too good
这么精彩的镜头
to delete.
删了多可惜啊
I'll keep it as a memento.
我得留着当纪念呢
Next year marks
我没记错的话明年
your 8th year at Dairui.
你就入职代瑞八年了
I'll throw you
到时候给你办一个
a party
庆祝仪式
and play
在仪式上把这视频
this video.
放出来
I've already got a theme:
主题我都给你想好了
"The Side of Ms. Rao You Didn't Know."
叫你所不知道的饶姐姐
Zhao Fanggang,
赵方刚我跟你讲
delete it right now!
现在立马给我删了快点
No way!
你弄死我也不会删的
Over my dead body!
不可能
Give me the phone.
手机给我拿来
-Don't grab it. -Hand it over!
你别抢 给我拿过来
Now.
快
My new phone.
我新买的手机
I just bought it half a year ago,
我刚买半年
for 10000 yuan!
一万块钱呢
Look,
你看
you've cracked the screen!
这屏幕又给你干碎了
You were the one
谁让你自己不小心
being careless.
拿不住
Great,
好了
now it won't even turn on.
开不了机了
How much did you say I owe you?
你刚说我欠你多少来着
8000.
八千
Now my phone won't even turn on...
我都没法开机了这都
Acting tough now?
你横什么横
Plus the 10000,
加上这一万
I'll give you 18000!
一万八
When will you pay me?
改天什么时候给呀
This lousy door...
这破门
Just wait!
等着吧
She's pretty strong.
整的力气还挺大
Greetings, President Lin.
林行长好
Your S1 has been
我看你们最近这个
really motivated lately.
拓展一部干劲很足啊
Morale is up.
士气全提起来了
I knew bringing you on board was right.
我就知道找你来准没错
Thank you.
老师您过奖了
Our team's spirit
我们一部的工作状态啊
has definitely improved,
确实好挺多
but we still need
不过业绩上
to boost our performance.
还得再提升
We're still a bit behind the targets
现在距离总行的要求
set by the head office.
确实还有些差距
By the way,
对了老师
I plan to focus more
我是想在年底之前
on attracting big clients
争取在存款方面
to increase
再多下点功夫
our total deposits
多拉几个大客户
by the end of the year.
争取把总额给提上去
Good.
好
I've noticed
我发现
that you always succeed
凡是你小子想干的事
in what you set your mind to.
就没有不成的
How's it going
最近跟女朋友
with your girlfriend?
相处得怎么样
[Haven't let work]
没有因为工作太忙
[interfere with your personal life, I hope.]
把恋爱耽误了吧
It's all right.
还好
When are you planning to get married?
那准备什么时候结婚
About that,
结婚的事
no rush.
还不急
Probably next year.
估计得到明年了吧
I'll be waiting for the good news.
那我等你们的好消息
Yu,
小齐啊
what gifts do young people
你们年轻人结婚
usually give for weddings
都兴送什么礼物啊
besides red envelopes?
就除了红包之外
It depends on
主要还是看您与他
how close you are
私交怎么样
with the person.
分人
For instance, what would be appropriate
就比如我跟小纪这关系
for my relationship with Mr. Ji?
送什么合适呢
Mr. Ji?
纪总啊
Is he getting married?
纪总要结婚了
No, no.
没有 没有
Young people tend to have shorter
我不是发现你们年轻人
romance before marriage.
都进展很快吗
So I want to be prepared.
得提前做个准备啊
Forget it.
开车吧啊
What's wrong?
干吗
You came in
来了之后
and didn't even have a look at me.
看都不看我一眼
You're on call 24/7
天天二十四小时待命
for your boss.
陪领导
It's so rare to see you,
好不容易见一面呢
and you're here acting all reserved.
还在这儿守男德呢
Are you going to get an award
也不知道谁给你颁奖
for this?
还是怎么的
I don't want any awards.
我也不想领这个奖
Such a
多有
strict sense of duty.
禁忌感啊
Next time,
下回
don't schedule me
别把我和阿姨的班
and nanny together.
排一起了
Next time?
别下回了
Nanny,
阿姨
you can leave now.
今天你可以先回家了
Keep the rest of the money.
多余的钱不用退了
Thanks, Weiyi.
谢谢依依
I'll be off then.
那我就回去了
Weiyi,
依依
see you tomorrow.
明天见
All right.
好嘞
Do you know
你知道
how hard it is to wait for your shift?
等你一次班有多难吗
It feels like
我觉得你这个恋爱
you're dating your boss,
不是在跟我谈
not me.
是在跟你们行长谈
Speaking of the boss,
说到行长
he asked me today
他今天问我
how much to give
说年轻人结婚
as a wedding gift for young people.
要随多少份子
Are you thinking...
你是不是想
No,
不是
it's Mr. Ji.
是我们行的纪总
But Weiyi,
不过惟依
shouldn't we also...
我们两个是不是也应该
What,
你说什么
Xiaoning is getting married?
涂筱柠要结婚了
Why didn't she tell me?
她怎么没跟我说呀
Wait,
不是
what does Mr. Ji
我们行的纪总
have to do with Xiaoning?
跟筱柠有什么关系
What's this?
干吗
I'm a rich woman.
我这么有钱
How can I let my best friend
怎么能让我闺蜜
eat instant noodles?
吃泡面呢
After a long day of work,
况且社畜一整天
you need something good
当然得吃点好的
to recharge.
才能回回血了
This meal costs
你这一顿
two days of my salary.
顶我两天工资了
What?
咋了
Did you do
你做什么
something wrong to me?
对不起我的事了
Don't I treat you well?
我平时对你不好吗
Yes, you do.
好啊
If you don't want this,
你要是不想吃这个
I can take you
等会儿下班我再带你
somewhere else after work.
去吃点别的好的
No need,
不用了
I haven't had much of an appetite.
我最近没什么胃口
All right then.
那好吧
Isn't this
这就是
Ji Yuheng's
纪昱恒那个什么
so-called first love, Tang something?
白月光唐什么卉吧
Keep it down.
小点声
Don't let others hear
别让别人听见
and cause trouble for Ji Yuheng.
给纪昱恒找麻烦
You're already a team,
婚还没结呢
and you're not even married yet.
这就成利益共同体了
We may not have registered,
我们两个虽然没有领证
but
但是
we're like a
也跟正常结婚夫妻
normal married couple.
没什么两样啊
We live together
住在一起
and share finances.
钱又放在一起
Causing trouble for him
那给他找麻烦
is like
不就等于
causing trouble for myself.
给自己找麻烦吗
Excuses.
借口
You clearly
我看呀
like him.
就是看上他了
So what?
那又怎么样
I don't know
不知道他到底
what he thinks.
是怎么想的呢
After the way
露营的时候
he treated you during camping,
他都对你那样了
you still don't get it?
你还不知道他的想法
I can't know for sure.
就是摸不准
If you're unsure, just ask him.
摸不准你就问
Send him a WeChat message right now.
现在马上发微信问
No, no, no.
别 别 别
When we first got together,
我们俩刚在一起的时候
it wasn't based on love;
就不是以爱情为前提
it was because we thought
而是觉得合适
it was suitable.
才在一起的
Now if I
那现在我一个人
raise my standards
单方面地想提高
for love,
对爱情的标准
wouldn't that be not fair to him?
是不是有点太过分了
Besides,
再说了
everyone has the right
每个人都有
to have a first love.
拥有白月光的权利吧
He hasn't done anything wrong.
人家也没错
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
since when
你现在怎么
did you become so indecisive?
这么婆婆妈妈的了
How am I indecisive?
我哪里是婆婆妈妈的
Fine.
行吧
Whatever.
事已至此
Let me
本小姐
give you some advice.
再给你指一条明路
Forget about
你就不要管他什么
his first love.
白月光不白月光的
You're the one who's closest to him now.
你现在是近水楼台耶
Just be flirty,
就直接暧昧勾引
be passionate, and take initiative.
激情缠绵连环操作
That's how
这样就能实现
you reach the harmony of life.
人类生命的大和谐了
Got it?
知道了吗
I'll pass.
还是算了
My exams are coming up,
我马上就要考试了
and I don't want to get distracted.
我不想因为这个事分心
Fine,
行
do whatever you want.
随便你吧
You two,
你们俩一个
one with a clumsy mouth,
嘴不利索
the other with a clumsy brain,
一个脑子不利索
really make a frustrating pair.
真是磨叽到一块去了
Don't come to me
以后你
with your
再有这种情感问题
emotional issues anymore.
可别再找我倾诉了
You're the one with problems,
情感有问题的是你
but I'm the one getting stressed out.
气进医院的是我
My breast
我这乳腺
hurts from the stress.
真是被气疼了
[Unlocked.]
已开锁
Xiaoning?
筱柠
[Locked.]
已关锁
Zhao Fanggang's friend?
赵方刚朋友
[Miss Tu,]
涂小姐
[sorry for the disturbance.]
不好意思打扰你了
[I was late and kept you waiting,]
上次迟到了一直让你等
[really sorry about that.]
实在不好意思
[Are you free this weekend?]
你这周末有空吗
[Let me take you out for a meal.]
我请你吃个饭赔个罪
She's in the shower.
她在洗澡
You're being disturbing.
确实有被你打扰到了
[You are...?]
您
Bank
代瑞
of Dairui employees
银行 员工
can't use their positions...
不得利用职务
Dairui
代瑞
can't...
不得
inconvenient...
不便利
When did you get back?
你什么时候回来的
Listening to the lecture
一边听题一边做卷子
and doing the exam at the same time?
三心二意啊
The exam is coming up.
那马上就要考试了
I wish
我现在恨不得
I could use
把我五官
all my senses to study.
能用上的都用上
Let me see.
我来看看
You got the sync rate indicator wrong,
同步率指标这个做错了
and the case analysis management
案件分析管理系统
system choice is incorrect.
这选得不对
Look again.
看看要选哪个
Let me see.
我看看啊
Choose A.
选一
A?
一
Are you sure?
确定吗
Not very sure.
不太确定
You've already got
这下面
the management mode application system
管理模式应用系统
question right,
你都已经写对了
how could you get this one wrong?
这题怎么还能做错啊
Think again.
再想想
Choose B.
选二
Sure?
确定
Correct.
答对了
[Forget about]
你就不要管他
[his first love.]
什么白月光不白月光的
[You're the one who's closest to him now.]
你现在是近水楼台耶
-You...
你
You go first.
你先说
I'm upset
我不开心
not because of my period.
不是因为生理期
I know.
我知道
Tang Yuhui may call me senior,
唐羽卉她虽然叫我师哥
but we hardly
但在学校的时候
ever talked
我们根本就
in school
没说过什么话
and we're not close.
也根本不熟
Her transfer to S1
她调到拓展一部
was a decision by the bank,
是行里的推荐
not arranged by me.
不是我安排的
If you weren't with me,
那如果你没跟我在一起
who would you be with?
你会跟谁在一起
If I was the first one to approach you
那如果高中毕业那年
after high school graduation,
第一个走向你的人是我
would you have said yes?
你会答应吗
True,
也是
life doesn't have
生活里
that many "what ifs."
哪有那么多如果呀
Back then, you didn't like me anyway.
那个时候你又不喜欢我
Life doesn't have "what ifs,"
生活里没有如果
so I would
所以我还是会
still be with you.
和你在一起
I won't think about this anymore.
我不想这件事了
The exam is coming up,
马上快考试了
and I've already wasted
我已经在这件事情上
too much time on this.
耽误太多时间了
No more thinking about it.
不想了 不想了
We'll talk about it
那等考完试以后
after the exam.
再说
This is so gross.
也太难吃了吧
I'm serious.
我真想问一下
How do
牛啊羊啊的
cows and sheep
它们怎么靠
survive on
吃这种叶子
leaves like this?
活这么多年的呀
Just deal with it
你就凑合吃吧
if you wanted
谁让你看人家
your abs back
齐郁的六块腹肌
after seeing Qi Yu's
非要找回自己的
six-pack.
马甲线的呀
Even if you're rich,
就算你有家财万贯
love makes everyone equal.
爱情面前人人平等
What are you doing?
你干吗
Since you're studying,
你反正也要学习
eat less.
那你少吃点
And
那谁
about his first love
你那天不是说什么
you mentioned,
白月光吗
you have to give her some pressure.
总得有点压力吧
Whose first love?
谁的白月光
First love is for memory.
挂天上的吗
So things have turned around?
听你这意思峰回路转了
He
他
doesn't like Tang Yuhui.
不喜欢唐羽卉
Then who's the cheerful girl
那你说的那个
with the high ponytail
爱扎高马尾
you mentioned?
笑声爽朗的女孩是谁
It's not you, right?
总不至于是你吧
I don't care who she is.
我管她是谁呢
I just want to study,
我现在就想好好学习
pass the exam,
顺利通过转正考试
and have a relaxing
然后就可以舒舒服服地
New Year day.
过一个元旦了
You're definitely
一看就是
in the sweetest stage of ambiguity.
最甜的暧昧期
Listen,
我可跟你说
just don't
你现在这个情况
rush things.
千万不要再往前冲了
Keep it balanced,
就主打一个游刃有余
under your control.
进退有度
Enjoy the push
互相拉扯
and pull.
你来我往的感觉
Didn't you just say
前两天不是还说
to flirt and get passionate?
暧昧勾引激情缠绵的吗
That was
那个时候的局面呢
when you loved him,
是你爱他
but he loved her.
但他爱她你俩都瞎
You both
那不得
needed to use your bodies
只能让诚实的身体
to find the answer.
来帮你们找找答案了
But now,
现在的情况
it's pure love,
走向了一个纯爱的路线
so take it slow.
那当然得小火慢炖
One step at a time.
走点心喽
My love advisor,
我的爱情顾问
what do you want to eat?
你想吃点什么
It's on me.
我请客
Tell me more.
你再给我说说呗
I want meat,
我想吃肉
lots of meat.
多给我来点肉
For your own good,
为了你好
let's skip that.
还是算了吧
Don't forget your abs.
你那马甲线
Oh right,
是噢
it's working well.
还挺有成效的
What's wrong?
咋了
The KPIs
领导定的
set by the boss
关键绩效指标
are too hard to meet.
太难完成了
It's almost the end of the year,
这眼看就年底了
and I'm still 20%
我还距目标
short of the target.
还差了五分之一呢
Will he cut my year-end bonus
他会不会因为这个
because of this?
扣我年终奖
I don't think so.
我觉得应该不会吧
He's only been here for 2 months,
领导刚来两个月
and
而且
the previous deficits
之前那些亏空啊
shouldn't be
耽误的时间
held against us.
应该不会算在咱们头上
Don't worry,
放心吧
he's not
他不是那么
unreasonable.
不讲道理的人
Li Xiang,
李想
don't just think, do it.
不能光想要做
Come on,
加油
work hard!
好好干
Xu Li,
许力哥
here's a deposit of 10 million dollars.
这是一千万美金的存款
Sign here
帮我签个字
to confirm my performance.
确认一下个人业绩
10 million?
一千万
Dollars?
美金
This is from a trading company
这是我爸之前
my dad worked with.
合作过的一个贸易公司
They handle
他们每天
large sums daily,
都有大额的资金往来
so I reached out
所以呢我就联系了一下
to their financial director
他们的财务总监
and moved
挪了一部分
some funds here.
到我们这边来结算
All right.
行
Which import-export company?
哪家进出口公司啊
Shunjue.
舜决
Okay, Yuhui,
行小唐
at this rate,
照你这个速度
you'll become a full-fledged
转成正式客户经理
account manager soon.
指日可待了
Thanks, Xu Li.
那我就借许力哥吉言
I'll keep pushing.
加油
[She definitely has connections.]
果然是有点来头啊
[A single call,]
一个电话
[and she gets]
就跟舜决
[10 million dollars from Shunjue.]
要来一千万美金
[I spent months]
我之前跟江总
[with Mr. Jiang and]
磨了几个月
[couldn't even get through their door.]
人家大门都没让我们进
[It's not the first day
她的背景
[you know about her background.]
你又不是第一天知道
[Do her parents]
不知道她爸妈
[need a son?]
还缺不缺儿子
[Your stupidity]
你的愚蠢
[never cease to amaze me.]
总是那么富有创造力
[Are we forming a clique?]
我们现在算搞小团体吗
[Not really.]
不算
[We're having a normal conversation]
我们这是部门师徒
[between mentors and mentee.]
正常情感交流
[Xiaoning is my mentee.]
小涂是我徒弟
[Stop trying to bond with us.]
跟你哪门子师门
Sir.
领导
Yuhui just signed a 10-million deposits.
小唐拉了一千万存款
Dollars!
美金
It's a big deal!
可不得了的呀
Did you?
是吗
Congratulations.
恭喜啊
Mr. Ji.
纪总
I'd like to take you out
晚上我想请大家
tonight to celebrate.
去庆祝一下
I'll take you all to karaoke.
我请大家唱歌
[Great!]
是啊
[We can go together.]
一块去啊
I'll pass.
我就不去了
I have a
晚上
family thing to do tonight.
我家里还有事
"A family thing".
家里有安排
Xiaoning.
小涂
Let me ask you.
问你个事
Just ask, Fanggang.
小赵哥你有事就说呗
You don't have to do it secretly.
鬼鬼祟祟地吓我一跳
I'm afraid I could reveal
我这不是怕把你的秘密
your secret.
给暴露了吗
What secret?
什么秘密
That brother of my friend.
就我那个朋友的弟弟
That blind date for you.
给你介绍的相亲对象
He called you.
给你打了电话
A man answered.
是个男的接的
And,
然后
he,
说
he hung up the phone
说了半句话
before he had chance to ask.
就把电话给挂了
Who's that?
谁呀
My dad.
我爸
Your, your dad?
你 你爸
You're a woman now, and he
你年纪也不小了
still filter blind dates for you?
你爸还帮你过滤男人
I'm having a hard time
我这现在考试
preparing for the test.
备考挺辛苦的
He doesn't want me to get distracted.
我爸不让我分心
The career matters more.
还是工作重要吗
Besides,
再说
all my dates have to
我找对象
get through to my parents.
我爸妈都要过关的
Daughters are delicate.
生女儿就是费心
Fathers
老父亲
are on their toes.
有操不完的心
But daughters are more lovable than sons.
但是女儿比儿子更可爱
[Naive.]
幼稚
[Xiaoning.]
小涂
[Don't talk about personal matters]
工作时间
[during working hours.]
不要聊私事
Feet up.
来
I haven't finished.
还没拖
You did that on purpose!
你故意的吧
Yes, I did.
我就是故意的
I told you
都说了
to take a break.
得休息一下
You've been studying too hard.
劳逸结合
Relax.
不能老学习
You're done cleaning.
你卫生打扫完了
But I'm not done reviewing.
我功课还没复习好呢
Give it back.
给我
No.
不给
No!
说了不给
Give it back.
给我
Never mind.
算了
Don't be mad.
别生气吗
I just think that
我就是觉得
you're studying hard every day.
你每天都在复习
Relaxation is good
总得劳逸结合
for better performance.
适当地休息一下
I'm not mad.
我没生气
Next week,
下个星期
mom will go home
妈不是可以出院
from the hospital.
回家住吗
I'm afraid I won't have time
我怕我到时候
to study anymore.
没有时间复习功课
So I have to
想着现在抓紧时间
study now.
复习一下吗
So that's the reason.
原来是因为这个
Don't worry.
不用担心
When she comes back,
等妈来了
I'll take care of her.
我来照顾她
No!
那怎么行啊
You'll be exhausted
你一个人
if you do it alone.
身体都累坏了
I can help you with it.
我可以帮你分担一下呀
Well,
那个
shouldn't we change
书房的床
the bed in the study?
是不是应该换一张啊
If Mom comes back...
妈要是回来的话
I said don't worry.
都说了不用担心
I've ordered a new bed
我已经订好了
and it's already delivered.
而且床已经到了
Do you know what to do next?
看出什么门道了吗
No.
没有
I just know that
我就看出来
Mr. Ji is clever and handy,
纪先生你聪明能干
while I'm clumsy
我笨手笨脚的
and not much help.
也帮不上什么忙
Well,
那行
when I'm the leader
那以后在行里啊
at work,
我是领导
you can be the leader
在家里
at home.
你是领导
If I'm the leader,
那我都是领导了
I won't let my man
更不能看着你
work alone.
一个人干活吧
How about
要不
I help you clean up.
我来帮你收拾收拾
I'll appreciate
那辛苦
your effort.
涂小姐了
You're welcome.
不辛苦
That's all
我也就只能
I can do.
干点这些活了
[The size is just right.]
刚刚好
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Get me something.
帮我拿个东西
What is it?
拿什么
The No. 5 nut on the floor.
地上的那个五号螺母
It's almost done.
差不多了
Yuheng.
昱恒
Maybe I should stay here
要不我在医院
for a while longer?
再住一阵吧
I'm getting used to living here.
这儿住习惯了
It's also convenient.
这儿也方便
Mom.
妈
The doctor said that
医生都已经说了
you can be discharged
您现在的情况
in your current condition.
是可以出院的
Besides, living
再说接您回去了
at home will
也有利于您的
help you recover.
病情的恢复啊
How about
那要不
I go back to
我回我那边去住
my own place?
也可以的
What if you
回您那边
get tired cooking
您自个儿做饭
by yourself when you live alone?
万一要是再累着怎么办
If I don't want to cook,
想做就做
I will order takeout.
不想做就叫外卖吗
I won't starve myself.
饿不着
You can't live on takeouts!
叫外卖怎么行啊
What's wrong?
怎么啦
Mom.
妈
You don't want to live with us?
你不想跟我们一起住啊
You're all busy
你们哪
at work.
上班都忙
Don't you have
你最近
an exam to prepare
不是还要
for these days?
复习考试吗
If I live with you,
那我在
I might weigh you down.
总归是有点打扰
So you still want to
那就是还是想
live with us.
跟我们一起住
That's all that matters.
那你怕什么呀
Are you afraid your daughter-in-law
怕我这个儿媳妇
won't get along?
不好相处
Nonsense!
净瞎说
Then come with us.
那就回去吧
Yuheng's been expecting your discharge
你儿子盼你盼得好久了
for a long time.
终于出院了
Let's go home.
走 回家
Go home.
回家
You're a nice couple,
这小两口感情真好
and nice sons and daughters.
还孝顺
You're so lucky.
你有福了
Enjoy your family time.
好好享子孙福
Okay.
好 好 好
Let's go.
走吧
Let's go home.
咱们回家
Be careful.
慢点
I need to
这子孙福啊
enjoy my family time.
我也得享享
Good bye.
走了啊
Get well soon.
您早日康复
Its lips are still moving.
它嘴在动
Don't be scared.
不用怕
No, no, no.
不行 不行 不行
How about you...
你要不
Don't just look!
你别光看着
Come and help me!
你过来帮帮我呀
You said to do it yourself.
不是你说的要自己来吗
Without help.
亲自动手
But it's not the same
但是它跟我查的攻略
as what I've read.
不太一样呀
According to the recipes,
人家的菜谱
the fish can go straight into the pan.
鱼可以直接下锅的
I take care of it.
还是我来吧
The fish must be cleaned first.
这鱼啊现在还没清理
Usually, this kind of work
一般这种活呢
is done by assistants.
都是小工去干
You're the chef.
你呢作为大厨
Leave it to me.
大材小用了
Okay.
是吧
Then I'll leave it to you.
那你先帮我收拾吧
I'll cook when you've done.
你收拾完了我再做
I'll take over from now on.
给我吧
Leave it to me.
你走吧
Are you sure?
确定
Be careful.
小心点啊
Don't forget flavorings.
葱姜蒜切了
Right.
好
Ji Yuheng!
纪昱恒
Help!
快来帮我一下
No.
不是
You're not leading us anywhere.
你别瞎带路啊
Is this the place?
是这儿吗
I think I got it right this time.
这回应该没错吧
This should be it.
应该就是这家
Don't you think you're overconfident?
你就是网上那种普信男
See? See?
你看 你看
I told you.
我说吧
You were right.
还真在这儿
Mom. Dad.
爸 妈
Come on in.
快 快快进来
Come in.
来 来 来
What about shoes?
换鞋吗
-Do I need to take them off? -Yes.
换不换鞋啊 换鞋换鞋
Here, Mrs. Ji.
来 亲家
Have some chicken soup.
你喝点这个乌鸡汤啊
Xiaoning's dad has been
筱柠爸爸
working on it all afternoon.
专门熬了一个下午的
It's tasteful.
可好喝了
Isn't it?
是吗
Try it.
尝一碗
Thank you
费心了
for all these dishes.
做这么多菜
It's okay.
一点都不麻烦
Try this.
尝尝怎么样
Mom, have a try.
妈您也来一碗吧
It smells so good.
好香啊
Why didn't you tell me before coming?
你们来也不说一声
If I knew you had made
早知道你们做了
such a great meal,
这么一桌子的菜
I wouldn't have
我就
almost
不差点
blown up the kitchen.
把家里厨房给烧了
Don't you have self-knowledge
就你那两把刷子
that you're not born to cook.
你还敢下厨
You know your daughter.
你的女儿你还不了解吗
She's showy.
爱逞能
Overconfident.
贼有自信
I have to say,
我跟你说
it's just like her father.
随她爸爸这点
Confident but humble.
普通而自信
I know Xiaoning
我知道筱柠啊
was trying to take care of me.
就是想照顾我
It doesn't matter
会不会做饭
if she can cook or not.
有什么关系吗
She's busy at work.
她本来工作就忙
She should have
回到家
had rest at home.
本来就该休息的嘛
From now on,
以后啊
you can focus on your work.
你们上班去
I stay here and cook for you.
我在家给你们做饭
That's not fair.
那哪儿行啊
Mrs. Ji,
我跟你说亲家
the kids brought you here
孩子们把你接到这儿来
to take care of you.
就是想好好照顾你啊
If you keep doing
你说你要是闲不住
chores for them,
忙这个忙那个
they'll feel sorry.
他们心里头也有负担的
He's right.
我觉得爸说得对
And I've got a caregiver.
而且我已经找好护工了
They cook during the day.
这护工呢白天做
I make dinner.
晚上我来做饭
That'll be great!
那太好了
Okay.
好 好
This is a good idea.
这安排好 对
Don't move.
别动
What?
咋了
Turn around.
转个头
You got a smudge on your nose.
吃到鼻子上了
It might be from my glove.
我刚才就是蹭了一下
Alright.
好 好 好
I'll listen to you.
我听你们的
Then
那
Yuheng
往后就让
will cook for us.
昱恒下厨
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
we can watch TV
咱们就坐沙发上
on sofa,
看电视啊
or enjoy ourselves.
玩啊
Wait until dinner's ready.
等着吃
-Right. -Wait until dinner's ready.
那就对了 吃现成的
Here.
来 来
Let's have a drink.
咱们碰一杯
Okay.
好
Thank you so much.
亲家 辛苦了 辛苦了
It's okay.
不辛苦 不辛苦
To your health!
身体健康
I'll cook again if you like.
好吃我改天再做
Here you are.
端过来啊
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Alright.
好了 好了
You get some rest, too.
你们也早点休息吧
I'm going to sleep.
我也睡了
How about
要不
I keep you company?
我陪您一起睡吧
I can take care of you
您晚上想喝口水什么的
if you want water or something.
我还能照顾一下你
Silly.
傻孩子
It's not like I can't move myself.
我又不是动不了
I'm okay.
我没什么事
You don't have to take care of me.
你照顾什么呀
I can't waste
我可不能打扰
the time of the newlyweds.
你们新婚夫妻
Go. Go.
快去 快去
She's used to sleeping alone.
妈习惯平时一个人睡
Let's go back to our room.
咱们先回吧
Go.
去吧
Okay.
嗯
Good night.
我们去了
I think
要不
I'll take the couch.
我还是去睡沙发吧
No way.
那不行
What if Mom sees us
万一被妈看见了
and thinks we're having a fight?
以为咱们俩吵架了呢
How would you explain?
怎么解释呀
The bed is big enough.
这个床也挺大的
We take each side.
咱们两个人一人睡一边
It can work.
应该没有问题
You sure?
你确定
Yeah.
我确定
Well,
那
which side do you prefer?
你喜欢哪边
I'll take this side.
我就睡这边吧
Then I'll take the other.
那我睡这边了
Then,
那你
you get sleep.
早点休息
I have to study for a while.
我还要复习一会儿功课
Don't stay up too late.
那你别太晚了
Good night.
早点休息
You're up?
起来了
You're up.
筱柠起来了
Breakfast is ready.
快来吃早饭
Okay.
好
A minute.
我马上来
Why didn't you
你自己起床
wake me up?
怎么不叫我呀
Mom would
你这样
think I'm lazy
妈会觉得我很懒惰
and I like to stay in bed.
喜欢赖床
It could ruin my image.
影响我形象的
Do you worry about your image
你会在你妈面前
in front of your own mom?
担心自己的形象呀
That's different.
那能一样吗
What's the difference?
怎么不一样的
We're a family now.
都是一家人了
Here. Have a seat.
来 坐
I got you coffee.
给你弄了咖啡
Your favorite.
合你胃口的
No.
不行
I'll prepare breakfast tomorrow.
明天一定要我做
You're studying so late every day.
你每天要复习到那么晚
Yesterday it was until 2:00 a.m.
昨天都到两点
If you have to make breakfast early,
再起来做个早餐
you're making your life
这好好的日子呀
a triathlon.
都得过成铁人三项了
Xiaoning.
筱柠啊
You only slept
你昨天
four hours yesterday.
才睡了四个小时啊
Mom, I'm used to it.
妈我习惯了
I don't sleep much.
觉少
Here.
来 来 来
You didn't sleep well.
你没睡好觉
Don't drink coffee.
不要喝咖啡了
It's bad for your heart.
对心脏不好
Have some milk.
喝牛奶
She's used to it.
都已经习惯了
Yeah.
对
I get sleepy at work in the morning
我要是不喝咖啡的话
if I don't drink coffee.
上午上班容易犯困
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
you have to study
你看你现在
for your test,
要 复习考试
and you have to work.
不能耽误工作的
Don't worry about
这家里的事
all these chores.
你就别操心了啊
You don't have to make breakfast.
做什么早餐啊
And don't treat me like a patient.
也别把妈当病人
Look at me.
你看我这不是
I'm perfectly fine.
好好的吗
But you two.
倒是你们俩
Don't take your good health for granted
不要老是仗着自己年轻
just because
不觉得
you're young.
什么都不当回事
That's how the health
那毛病就是这么
breaks down,
一点 一点
little by little.
一点地攒起来的
Okay.
好
Alright.
好了 好了
It's still early for work.
离上班时间还早
Have the breakfast and
先吃点东西
go back to sleep.
再回去睡个觉
Extra sleep is the best.
回笼觉最香了
Let's eat.
开动吧
It's year end. Don't stall any longer.
年底了别拖了啊
Don't pretend it didn't happen.
跟我玩若无其事
Ms. Rao.
饶经理
I'm the debtor.
我是债主
You owe my money.
你是欠钱的
You'd be forced to be my servant
这要搁万恶的旧社会
if it's in feudal society.
你要给我当长工的
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
You do look like
你那个气质看着吧
an evil landlord.
确实挺像周扒皮的
Besides,
再说了
I didn't say I was going to renege.
我说不还钱了吗
I'll
我
pay you back as soon as
第四季度的绩效
I get my fourth quarter bonus.
发了就给你
I wonder,
我就纳闷了
don't you save any money?
你平时一点钱都不存
As a debtor,
作为一个债主
don't you have too many questions?
你管得是不是有点多
What's it to you
我存不存钱
if I save money or not?
跟你有什么关系
What if you have an emergency
那万一家里有个急事
and you need money?
需要用钱你怎么办呢
It's easy.
好办呀
If I don't need much,
小钱
I use my credit card.
信用卡
If it's much, I get a loan.
大钱做贷款
If that wouldn't suffice,
再不济
my car, my bags,
我的小车
I can put them up
还有我的小包包
as collateral.
都可以做抵押
Besides,
再说了
I've been in the bank for years.
我在银行干这么多年
I have a steady income.
我有稳定的收入
I have a financial mindset.
我还有金融思维
You think I'm gonna plunge into
我还能让我的经济
abject poverty?
崩塌了
Is that all?
好了吗
Where's my money?
还钱
I told you I'll pay you back
不是跟你说了吗
when I get my fourth quarter
第四季度绩效发了
bonus.
就给你
You're a banker.
你一个干银行的
Don't you know that
你不会不知道我这钱
money in the bank
存在银行一天
accrues interest?
就能滚一天的利吧
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
You're talking to me
跟我在这儿说半天
for the interest?
就是为了那点利息呀
Easy.
简单
I'll pay you back
我按照咱们银行
at a percentage point over
固定存款利率
the fixed deposit rate of our bank.
多一个点给你
Not enough.
不够
1.5 percentage point.
一点五个点
Deal.
成交
We'll count it from the day you got drunk.
从你喝醉那天开始算
You evil landlord.
周扒皮
I don't care what you call me.
周扒皮就周扒皮
Espresso.
意式浓缩
Mr. Zhao can finally take care of himself.
我们赵经理突然长手了
You don't need Xiaoning to serve you?
不用小涂帮你泡咖啡了
I don't dare to disturb her.
我哪敢找她呀
Look at her.
你看
She's been studying so hard.
她最近复习那劲头
I won't take a risk to waste
万一考试没考过
her time making my coffee.
别到时候因为
I'd feel guilty for a long-long time
是我让她帮我泡咖啡
if she fails the test
浪费她时间
because of me.
我会愧疚半年的
Don't jinx it.
你怎么这么乌鸦嘴
She hasn't taken the test yet.
人家还没考
Don't say anything ominous.
你就咒人家考不过
I didn't mean that.
我不是那意思
She's been studying
我是看她最近
at the cost of her health.
不吃不喝的
She's pining away.
人都快蔫儿了
The exam is in two days.
还有两天就考试了
She'd be so sad
别到时候没考过
if she shouldn't pass the test,
她肯定会心情不好的
wouldn't she?
对吧
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
You are so busy all day long.
您真是操不完的心
You need to collect a debt,
又得催债
and to take care of Xiaoning.
还得看着人家小涂考试
So busy.
忙死了
Xiaoning.
小涂
You got a cold?
你感冒了
Seems so, Fanggang.
有一点小赵哥
I've got malva nut.
我这儿有胖大海
I'll give you some.
我拿给你
No, thank you.
不用了
I'm okay.
我没事
Xiaoning.
小涂
Are you okay?
还好吧
I've taken my pills.
吃过药了
Thank you for your concern.
谢谢纪总关心啊
I'm okay.
没事
Are you sure?
确定
I'm fine. Really.
真没事
Sorry, Xiaoning.
对不起啊小涂
I forgot where
我 我不知道
my malva nut is.
藏哪儿去了
Uh,
那个
I'll order it online.
我给你点外卖
Where's my phone?
我手机呢
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Wake up.
醒醒了
What?
怎么了
Was I too noisy?
我吵醒你了
It's late.
太晚了
Go back to bed.
回床上睡去吧
I'll carry you.
我抱你过去
Good night.
晚安